http://www.smus.ca/privacy

Join In
Access our news, photos, video and upcoming events then join the conversation through Facebook, Twitter and our blogs
Individual Privacy
We at SMUS want you, our parents, students and staff, to be aware of how and why we handle your personal information. We work hard to respect and maintain your privacy. However, the very nature of our business is such that the collection, use and disclosure of personal information is fundamental to the services we provide.
SMUS has adopted these Privacy Principles, which apply to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information.
Personal information, for the purposes of these Privacy Principles, means information that identifies an individual. For example: an individual's name, birth date, address, age, health and financial information is personal information which SMUS may collect, use and in certain circumstances, where necessary, disclose, in the course of carrying on business.
These Privacy Principles may be modified from time to time. You may obtain our most up to date version from this web page or by contacting us at the address set out below in the section called "Contacting the SMUS Privacy Officer".
1. Consent and Personal Information
SMUS obtains consent to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information, except where inappropriate.
In obtaining consent to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information, the purpose for which information is collected, used or disclosed is either obvious by the very nature of the transaction or if not, we state the purpose, either at or before the time the information is collected. When we do collect personal information, we collect only that personal information which is necessary to such obvious or stated purpose.
You may decline to consent, or revoke your consent, to the collection and use of your personal information for these purposes but if you do the services that we can provide to you may be limited.
SMUS may also collect and use personal information for school advancement and development purposes or for Parents' Auxiliary activities. This may result in identifying and communicating with individuals who are likely to participate in school advancement and development or Parents' Auxiliary activities. Your consent to this use of your personal information is voluntary. You may opt not to have us use your personal information for this purpose. If you do this, we will collect and use your personal information only for school purposes and in accordance with our contractual rights and obligations, but we will not use your personal information for advancement, development or Parents Auxiliary purposes. Please refer to the section of these Privacy Principles called "Contacting the SMUS Privacy Officer" for information on how to decline or revoke your consent to the use of your personal information for advancement or development purposes.
2. Collecting Personal Information
Whenever practical, we collect information directly from the individual concerned. We log information about visitor activity on our website to help us monitor site performance and provide you with a better experience.
We also collect information for the purpose of marketing, including online advertising opportunities such as retargeting. Retargeting requires that cookies are stored on your computer. This is standard practice on the web and these cookies are not harmful. They inform SMUS’s advertising partners that you previously visited a SMUS website but they do not provide those partners with personally identifiable information. If you wish to opt-out of the most common form of retargeting, Google advertising, you can set your preferences at www.google.com/settings/ads.
3. Using Personal Information
We use personal information in accordance with the consent provided by the individual to whom the information relates, in accordance with these Privacy Principles, our contractual rights and obligations and the law.
Personal information shall not be used by SMUS employees and representatives for purposes other than as required in the performance of their employment duties.
4. Accuracy of Your Personal Information
SMUS maintains procedures to ensure that the information we collect and use is accurate, up-to-date, and as complete as possible. However, we rely on you to disclose all material information to us and to inform us of any changes. You may, with proof of entitlement, request to access and if applicable request that we correct information in our possession. You may make this request by writing to our Privacy Officer at the address set out below in the section called "Contacting the SMUS Privacy Officer".
5. Safeguarding your Information
We apply appropriate safeguards to our computer networks and physical files and we restrict access to personal information about you to those SMUS employees and authorized administrators who need to know that information in order to administer your services.
6. Disclosure of Personal Information
We do not sell our customer lists or other personal information.
7. Retention and Access to Your Personal Information
We retain personal information only for so long as is necessary to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected and to meet our legal and contractual obligations. If personal information is no longer required, it will be destroyed or rendered anonymous. If you have a right of access, you or a person authorized in writing to act on your behalf may, with satisfactory identification and proof of entitlement, request access or, if applicable, request a correction of your personal information which SMUS has in its possession. The right to access is not absolute. For example, you do not have a right to access and we may decline your request for access, if the information requested is subject to a legal privilege. We do not provide personal health information directly to individuals unless the individual provided it directly to us. Instead we provide access to personal health information through the individual's health care professional.
8. Contacting the SMUS Privacy Officer
The Privacy Officer
St. Michaels University School
3400 Richmond Rd
Victoria, BC V8P 4P5
[email protected]
Please contact us if you:
have questions about our privacy practices;
wish to access or correct your personal information; or
wish to decline or revoke your consent to the use, collection or disclosure of your personal information for advancement, development or Parents' Auxiliary purposes.
Please include your name, address, and if applicable your student number.
St. Michaels University School is a co-educational, independent day and boarding school of 1000 students from Kindergarten to Grade 12 in Victoria, BC, Canada.
HomeApply NowContact SMUSAlumniWilson ArchivesAnnual AppealPrivacyPublicationsDiscover SMUSCOVID-19 UpdatesDiscover Our PromiseMission, Vision and ValuesStrategic PlanOur Academic ApproachSMUS at a GlanceHead's Welcome MessageOur HistoryGovernance and FoundationCareers at SMUSSMUS Staff DirectoryFacility RentalsMedia RoomPublicationsAccreditation and AssociationsAdmissionsGetting StartedApplication ProcessRequest a MeetingVirtual EventsAdmissions TravelTuition and FeesAdmissions FAQsPublicationsMeet Our TeamProgramsJunior SchoolMiddle SchoolSenior SchoolBoardingELL/ESLPost-Secondary PreparationExternal ProgramsCommunitySMUS CommunityPhoto GalleryLive Video StreamingParents' AuxiliaryCampus Shop and UniformDiningExternal ProgramsPublicationsStudent Services and SupportActivities, Clubs and CouncilsAbsences and Academic Policies
logos
© St. Michaels University School • 3400 Richmond Road, Victoria, B.C. • Canada V8P 4P5 • Ph: (250) 592-2411 • Fx: (250) 592-2812
